<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part One: Economics on LW Studio</title>
    <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part One: Economics on LW Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <copyright>CC-BY-4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 On Property and Exploitation</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-01-on-property-and-exploitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-01-on-property-and-exploitation/</guid>
      <description>1 On Property and Exploitation #  (with Hans-Hermann Hoppe)
1 #  Whenever one says “I own a house,” what one normally means is: I have the right to determine how that particular resource—described in objective, physical terms—is to be employed; I am free to employ it for any purpose whatsoever, provided that in so doing I do not impair the physical integrity of resources owned by others; I am likewise entitled to expect that the physical integrity of my resource, my house, remains unaffected by the actions others perform with the physical resources at their disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Toward a Universal Libertarian Theory of Weapon Control</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-02-toward-a-universal-theory-of-gun-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-02-toward-a-universal-theory-of-gun-control/</guid>
      <description>2 Toward a Universal Libertarian Theory of Gun (Weapon) Control: A Spatial and Geographical Analysis #  (with Matthew Block)
No rational person can doubt that chemists must pick their way through an ethical minefield. The Nazi ovens owed their properties and attributes to members of this profession, directly or indirectly. Nor can it be denied that biologists are often faced with moral quandaries; genetic cloning and germ warfare spring readily to mind in this context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Environmentalism and Economic Freedom</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-03-environmentalism-and-economic-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-03-environmentalism-and-economic-freedom/</guid>
      <description>3 Environmentalism and Economic Freedom: The Case for Private Property Rights #  This paper shall attempt to reconcile environmentalism and economic freedom.
Before making this seemingly quixotic endeavor, we must be sure we are clear on both concepts. Environmentalism may be noncontroversially defined as a philosophy which sees great benefit in clean air and water, and to a lowered rate of species extinction. Environmentalists are particularly concerned with the survival and enhancement of endangered species such as trees, elephants, rhinos and whales, and with noise and dust pollution, oil spills, greenhouse effects and the dissipation of the ozone layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Enterprising Education</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-04-enterprising-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-04-enterprising-education/</guid>
      <description>4 Enterprising Education: Doing Away with the Public School System #  (with Andrew Young)
Besides national defense, no government-provided service enjoys as much exemption from scrutiny as the provision and subsidization of primary public education. Even presumed champions of the free market, such as Milton Friedman, support the government subsidization of education through high school:
 We have always been proud, and with good reason, of the widespread availability of schooling to all and the role that public schooling has played in fostering the assimilation of newcomers into our society, preventing fragmentation and divisiveness, and enabling people from different cultural and religious backgrounds to live together in harmony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Labor Relations, Unions and Collective Bargaining</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-05-labor-relations-unions-and-collective-bargaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-05-labor-relations-unions-and-collective-bargaining/</guid>
      <description>5 Labor Relations, Unions and Collective Bargaining: A Political Economic Analysis #  It is not difficult to document the fact that many segments of our society extol the virtues of unionism, as commonly practiced. Some people defend unions as a means of promoting employment. Others feel that “social justice” is a sufficient warrant for this curious institution. So deeply embedded in our folkways is the concept that unions are legitimate institutions that many mainline religious organizations have even gone so far as to invite them to organize their own church employees—on what they see as moral grounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Is There a Right To Unionize?</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-06-is-there-a-right-to-unionize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-06-is-there-a-right-to-unionize/</guid>
      <description>6 Is There a Right To Unionize? #  I resist the notion that we have a “right to unionize” or that unionization is akin, or, worse, an implication of, the right to freely associate. Yes, theoretically, a labor organization could limit itself to organizing a mass quit unless they got what they wanted. That would indeed be an implication of the law of free association.
But every union with which I am familiar reserves the right to employ violence (that is, to initiate violence) against competing workers, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Free Market Transportation</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-07-free-market-transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-07-free-market-transportation/</guid>
      <description>7 Free Market Transportation: Denationalizing the Roads #  Were a government to demand the sacrifice of 46,700 citizens1 each year, there is no doubt that an outraged public would revolt. If an organized religion were to plan the immolation of 523,335 of the faithful in a decade,2 there is no question that it would be toppled. Were there a Manson-type cult that murdered 790 people to celebrate Memorial Day, 770 to usher in the Fourth of July, 915 to commemorate Labor Day, 960 at Thanksgiving, and solemnized Christmas with 355 more deaths,3 surely The New York Times would wax eloquent about the carnage, calling for the greatest manhunt this nation has ever seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Public Goods and Externalities</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-08-public-goods-and-externalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-08-public-goods-and-externalities/</guid>
      <description>8 Public Goods and Externalities: The Case of Roads #  When government monopolization of the roadways is discussed by economists, the “externalities” argument is usually raised. The argument is said to be simple, clear, and irrefutable. In fact, none of these terms really apply. Let us consider the argument closely.
The externalities argument is based upon a distinction between private goods and services, the use of which benefits only the consumer in question, and public or collective goods, consumption of which necessarily affects the welfare of third or “external” parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 The Gold Standard</title>
      <link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-09-the-gold-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-09-the-gold-standard/</guid>
      <description>9 The Gold Standard: A Critique of Friedman, Mundell, Hayek and Greenspan from the Free Enterprise Perspective #  This is an essay which takes as its jumping off point the free enterprise system. It then attempts to evaluate the contributions of four distinguished scholars to monetary theory in general, and to an evaluation of the gold standard in particular. I take for granted the general case for markets, competition, economic freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
