<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Part Two: Human Rights on LW Studio</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/</link><description>Recent content in Part Two: Human Rights on LW Studio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>CC-BY-4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>10 The Nonaggression Axiom of Libertarianism</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism"&gt;
 10 The Nonaggression Axiom of Libertarianism
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nonaggression axiom is the lynchpin of the philosophy of libertarianism. It states, simply, that it shall be legal for anyone to do anything he wants, provided only that he not initiate (or threaten) violence against the person or legitimately owned property of another. That is, in the free society, one has the right to manufacture, buy or sell any good or service at any mutually agreeable terms. Thus, there would be no victimless crime prohibitions, price controls, government regulation of the economy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>11 Libertarianism, Positive Obligations and Property Abandonment</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment-childrens-rights"&gt;
 11 Libertarianism, Positive Obligations and Property Abandonment: Children’s Rights
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment-childrens-rights"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basic premise of libertarianism (Cuzán 1979; de Jasay 1985, 1997; Friedman 1978; Hoppe 1989; Hummel 1990; Kinsella 1996a; Morriss 1998; Rothbard 1978, 1982; Skoble 1995; Sechrest 1999; Stringham 1998; Tinsley 1998) is that there are no positive obligations. No one is forced to contribute to charity. Good Samaritan laws mandating that people come to the aid of those in trouble (say, an unconscious person) are incompatible with libertarianism. To take an extreme case, there would be no law against refusing to toss a life preserver to a drowning man even if one could do so with minimal effort, and his death would occur otherwise. In this political philosophy, there are only negative obligations.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It is prohibited, and a punishable criminal offense, to initiate or even threaten violence against anyone or his justly acquired property.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>12 Social Justice</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-12-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-12-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="12-social-justice"&gt;
 12 Social Justice
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#12-social-justice"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On many university campuses, there is a push on to promote social justice. There are two ways to define “social justice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, this concept may be defined substantively. Here, it is typically associated with left-wing or socialist analyses, policies and prescriptions. For example, poverty is caused by unbridled capitalism; the solution is to heavily regulate markets, or ban them outright. Racism and sexism account for the relative plight of racial minorities and women; laws should be passed prohibiting their exercise. Greater reliance on government is required as the solution of all sorts of social problems. The planet is in great danger from environmental despoliation, due to an unjustified reliance on private property rights. Taxes are too low; they should be raised. Charity is an insult to the poor, who must obtain more revenues by right, not condescension. Diversity is the sine qua non of the fair society. Discrimination is one of the greatest evils to have ever beset mankind. Use of terminology such as “mankind” is sexist, and constitutes hate speech.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>13 Discrimination</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-13-discrimination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-13-discrimination/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="13-discrimination-an-interdisciplinary-analysis"&gt;
 13 Discrimination: An Interdisciplinary Analysis
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#13-discrimination-an-interdisciplinary-analysis"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discrimination has been treated by large parts of the academic community as though it were not amenable to logical analysis, be it economic, ethical or political; as though the very consideration of alternative viewpoints were somehow unsavory. The philosophy of “feminism,” “human rights,” “multiculturalism,” and “political correctness” have so permeated intellectual discussion that criticisms of the mainstream view take on an aura of illegitimacy at the outset, even before arguments are heard in their behalf. This is highly unfortunate. If nothing else, John Stuart Mill’s On Liberty should give us pause before closing our minds to alternative perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>14 A Libertarian Case for Free Immigration</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration"&gt;
 14 A Libertarian Case for Free Immigration
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None are too many.”—Reply of an anonymous senior official in the government of Canadian Prime Minister McKenzie King to the question, “How many Jews fleeing Nazi Germany should be allowed into this country?”&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All merchants shall have safe and secure exit from England and entry to England, with the right to tarry there and to move about as well by land as by water, for buying and selling by the ancient and right customs, quite from all evil tolls, except (in time of war) such merchants as are of the land at war with us. And if such are found in our land at the beginning of the war, they shall be detained, without injury to their bodies or goods, until information be received by us, or by our chief justiciar, how the merchants of our land found in the land at war with us are treated; and if our men are safe there, the others shall be safe in our land.&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>15 Sucession</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-15-secession/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-15-secession/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="15-secession"&gt;
 15 Secession
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#15-secession"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law of free association is a crucially important implication of the rights of private property (in physical material, and in our own bodies). For if we cannot freely associate with others on a mutually-voluntary basis, our property rights are to that extent abrogated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most serious denigration of property rights in persons and thus in free association is, of course, murder. No one favors such behavior (killing in self-defense is entirely another matter) so this is not at all controversial. Another grave violation of the libertarian code of nonaggression against nonaggressors and their property is slavery (or kidnapping, which is short-term slavery). This, too, is nondebatable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>16 Legalize Drugs Now!</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-16-legalize-drugs-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-16-legalize-drugs-now/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="16-legalize-drugs-now-an-analysis-of-the-benefits-of-legalized-drugs"&gt;
 16 Legalize Drugs Now! An Analysis of the Benefits of Legalized Drugs
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#16-legalize-drugs-now-an-analysis-of-the-benefits-of-legalized-drugs"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(with Meaghan Cussen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="basic-constitutional-rights"&gt;
 Basic Constitutional Rights
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#basic-constitutional-rights"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many argue that drug prohibition protects addicts from themselves by exerting parental control over their behavior. This government-enforced control, the anti-drug laws, strictly monitors addicts treatment of their own bodies. For example, the government decides that it wants to protect Fred Brown from destroying his body. The government, therefore, outlaws narcotics and, in effect, takes control of Fred’s body. Under the United States Constitution and the anti-slavery laws, this hegemony should not happen. The guiding principles of the United States, iterated both in the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution, protect Fred’s basic civil liberties to “pursue his own happiness” as long as he doesn’t infringe on others’ rights to life and property. With prohibition, Fred no longer has this constitutional right. He no longer controls his own body. Regulation has stripped him of his civil liberty. Fred’s role of “owner of his own body” is taken away from him. This has, in effect, made him a slave.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>17 Libertarianism and Libertinism</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-17-libertarianism-and-libertinism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-17-libertarianism-and-libertinism/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="17-libertarianism-and-libertinism"&gt;
 17 Libertarianism and Libertinism
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#17-libertarianism-and-libertinism"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is perhaps no greater confusion in all of political economy than that between libertarianism and libertinism. That they are commonly taken for one another is an understatement of the highest order. For several reasons, it is difficult to compare and contrast libertarianism and libertinism. First and most important, on some issues the two views do closely resemble one another, at least superficially. Second—perhaps purely by accident, perhaps due to etymological considerations—the two words not only sound alike, but are spelled almost identically. It is all the more important, then, to distinguish between the very different concepts these words represent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>