<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building Blocks Liberty on LW Studio</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/</link><description>Recent content in Building Blocks Liberty on LW Studio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-tw</language><copyright>CC-BY-4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Acknowledgements</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/01-acknowledgements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/01-acknowledgements/</guid><description>Acknowledgements # This book could not have been published without the advice and contribution of many libertarian colleagues and friends.
We are most grateful to Llewellyn H. Rockwell, Jr., President of the Ludwig von Mises Institute, for helping us pursue this project and writing a wonderful Foreword.
We should like to thank the editors of the International Journal of Value-Based Management, Ethics, Place and Environment, Journal of Business Ethics, Journal of Social, Political and Economic Studies, Managerial Finance, International Journal of Social Economics, Journal of Libertarian Studies, American Journal of Economics and Sociology for permission to reprint Professor Block’s articles previously published by these prestigious journals.</description></item><item><title>Foreword</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/02-foreword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/02-foreword/</guid><description>Foreword # Murray Rothbard, in his life, was known as Mr. Libertarian. We can make a solid case that the title now belongs to Walter Block, a student of Rothbard’s whose own vita is as thick as a phone book, as diverse as Wikipedia. Whether he is writing on economic theory, ethics, political secession, drugs, roads, education, monetary policy, social theory, unions, political language, or anything else, his prose burns with a passion for this single idea: if human problems are to be solved, the solution is to be found by permitting greater liberty.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/03-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/03-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction # This book Building Blocks for Liberty: Critical Essays by Walter Block is dedicated to the notion that libertarianism is not only a political economic philosophy that is powerful and insightful, but it is also unique; it is neither of the right nor of the left (Walter Block, “Libertarianism is Unique; It Belongs Neither to the Right Nor the Left; A Critique of the Views of Long, Holcombe, and Baden on the left, Hoppe, Feser and Paul on the right,” Journal of Libertarian Studies, 2010).</description></item><item><title>1 On Property and Exploitation</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-01-on-property-and-exploitation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-01-on-property-and-exploitation/</guid><description>1 On Property and Exploitation # (with Hans-Hermann Hoppe)
1 # Whenever one says “I own a house,” what one normally means is: I have the right to determine how that particular resource—described in objective, physical terms—is to be employed; I am free to employ it for any purpose whatsoever, provided that in so doing I do not impair the physical integrity of resources owned by others; I am likewise entitled to expect that the physical integrity of my resource, my house, remains unaffected by the actions others perform with the physical resources at their disposal.</description></item><item><title>2 Toward a Universal Libertarian Theory of Weapon Control</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-02-toward-a-universal-theory-of-gun-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-02-toward-a-universal-theory-of-gun-control/</guid><description>2 Toward a Universal Libertarian Theory of Gun (Weapon) Control: A Spatial and Geographical Analysis # (with Matthew Block)
No rational person can doubt that chemists must pick their way through an ethical minefield. The Nazi ovens owed their properties and attributes to members of this profession, directly or indirectly. Nor can it be denied that biologists are often faced with moral quandaries; genetic cloning and germ warfare spring readily to mind in this context.</description></item><item><title>3 Environmentalism and Economic Freedom</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-03-environmentalism-and-economic-freedom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-03-environmentalism-and-economic-freedom/</guid><description>3 Environmentalism and Economic Freedom: The Case for Private Property Rights # This paper shall attempt to reconcile environmentalism and economic freedom.
Before making this seemingly quixotic endeavor, we must be sure we are clear on both concepts. Environmentalism may be noncontroversially defined as a philosophy which sees great benefit in clean air and water, and to a lowered rate of species extinction. Environmentalists are particularly concerned with the survival and enhancement of endangered species such as trees, elephants, rhinos and whales, and with noise and dust pollution, oil spills, greenhouse effects and the dissipation of the ozone layer.</description></item><item><title>4 Enterprising Education</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-04-enterprising-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-04-enterprising-education/</guid><description>4 Enterprising Education: Doing Away with the Public School System # (with Andrew Young)
Besides national defense, no government-provided service enjoys as much exemption from scrutiny as the provision and subsidization of primary public education. Even presumed champions of the free market, such as Milton Friedman, support the government subsidization of education through high school:
We have always been proud, and with good reason, of the widespread availability of schooling to all and the role that public schooling has played in fostering the assimilation of newcomers into our society, preventing fragmentation and divisiveness, and enabling people from different cultural and religious backgrounds to live together in harmony.</description></item><item><title>5 Labor Relations, Unions and Collective Bargaining</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-05-labor-relations-unions-and-collective-bargaining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-05-labor-relations-unions-and-collective-bargaining/</guid><description>5 Labor Relations, Unions and Collective Bargaining: A Political Economic Analysis # It is not difficult to document the fact that many segments of our society extol the virtues of unionism, as commonly practiced. Some people defend unions as a means of promoting employment. Others feel that “social justice” is a sufficient warrant for this curious institution. So deeply embedded in our folkways is the concept that unions are legitimate institutions that many mainline religious organizations have even gone so far as to invite them to organize their own church employees—on what they see as moral grounds.</description></item><item><title>6 Is There a Right To Unionize?</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-06-is-there-a-right-to-unionize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-06-is-there-a-right-to-unionize/</guid><description>6 Is There a Right To Unionize? # I resist the notion that we have a “right to unionize” or that unionization is akin, or, worse, an implication of, the right to freely associate. Yes, theoretically, a labor organization could limit itself to organizing a mass quit unless they got what they wanted. That would indeed be an implication of the law of free association.
But every union with which I am familiar reserves the right to employ violence (that is, to initiate violence) against competing workers, e.</description></item><item><title>7 Free Market Transportation</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-07-free-market-transportation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-07-free-market-transportation/</guid><description>7 Free Market Transportation: Denationalizing the Roads # Were a government to demand the sacrifice of 46,700 citizens1 each year, there is no doubt that an outraged public would revolt. If an organized religion were to plan the immolation of 523,335 of the faithful in a decade,2 there is no question that it would be toppled. Were there a Manson-type cult that murdered 790 people to celebrate Memorial Day, 770 to usher in the Fourth of July, 915 to commemorate Labor Day, 960 at Thanksgiving, and solemnized Christmas with 355 more deaths,3 surely The New York Times would wax eloquent about the carnage, calling for the greatest manhunt this nation has ever seen.</description></item><item><title>8 Public Goods and Externalities</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-08-public-goods-and-externalities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-08-public-goods-and-externalities/</guid><description>8 Public Goods and Externalities: The Case of Roads # When government monopolization of the roadways is discussed by economists, the “externalities” argument is usually raised. The argument is said to be simple, clear, and irrefutable. In fact, none of these terms really apply. Let us consider the argument closely.
The externalities argument is based upon a distinction between private goods and services, the use of which benefits only the consumer in question, and public or collective goods, consumption of which necessarily affects the welfare of third or “external” parties.</description></item><item><title>9 The Gold Standard</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-09-the-gold-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-1-economics/part-1-09-the-gold-standard/</guid><description>9 The Gold Standard: A Critique of Friedman, Mundell, Hayek and Greenspan from the Free Enterprise Perspective # This is an essay which takes as its jumping off point the free enterprise system. It then attempts to evaluate the contributions of four distinguished scholars to monetary theory in general, and to an evaluation of the gold standard in particular. I take for granted the general case for markets, competition, economic freedom.</description></item><item><title>10 The Nonaggression Axiom of Libertarianism</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-10-the-nonaggression-axiom-of-libertarianism/</guid><description>10 The Nonaggression Axiom of Libertarianism # The nonaggression axiom is the lynchpin of the philosophy of libertarianism. It states, simply, that it shall be legal for anyone to do anything he wants, provided only that he not initiate (or threaten) violence against the person or legitimately owned property of another. That is, in the free society, one has the right to manufacture, buy or sell any good or service at any mutually agreeable terms.</description></item><item><title>11 Libertarianism, Positive Obligations and Property Abandonment</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-11-libertarianism-positive-obligations-and-property-abandonment/</guid><description>11 Libertarianism, Positive Obligations and Property Abandonment: Children’s Rights # A basic premise of libertarianism (Cuzán 1979; de Jasay 1985, 1997; Friedman 1978; Hoppe 1989; Hummel 1990; Kinsella 1996a; Morriss 1998; Rothbard 1978, 1982; Skoble 1995; Sechrest 1999; Stringham 1998; Tinsley 1998) is that there are no positive obligations. No one is forced to contribute to charity. Good Samaritan laws mandating that people come to the aid of those in trouble (say, an unconscious person) are incompatible with libertarianism.</description></item><item><title>12 Social Justice</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-12-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-12-social-justice/</guid><description>12 Social Justice # On many university campuses, there is a push on to promote social justice. There are two ways to define “social justice.”
First, this concept may be defined substantively. Here, it is typically associated with left-wing or socialist analyses, policies and prescriptions. For example, poverty is caused by unbridled capitalism; the solution is to heavily regulate markets, or ban them outright. Racism and sexism account for the relative plight of racial minorities and women; laws should be passed prohibiting their exercise.</description></item><item><title>13 Discrimination</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-13-discrimination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-13-discrimination/</guid><description>13 Discrimination: An Interdisciplinary Analysis # Discrimination has been treated by large parts of the academic community as though it were not amenable to logical analysis, be it economic, ethical or political; as though the very consideration of alternative viewpoints were somehow unsavory. The philosophy of “feminism,” “human rights,” “multiculturalism,” and “political correctness” have so permeated intellectual discussion that criticisms of the mainstream view take on an aura of illegitimacy at the outset, even before arguments are heard in their behalf.</description></item><item><title>14 A Libertarian Case for Free Immigration</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-14-a-libertarian-case-for-free-immigration/</guid><description>14 A Libertarian Case for Free Immigration # “None are too many.”—Reply of an anonymous senior official in the government of Canadian Prime Minister McKenzie King to the question, “How many Jews fleeing Nazi Germany should be allowed into this country?”1 All merchants shall have safe and secure exit from England and entry to England, with the right to tarry there and to move about as well by land as by water, for buying and selling by the ancient and right customs, quite from all evil tolls, except (in time of war) such merchants as are of the land at war with us.</description></item><item><title>15 Sucession</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-15-secession/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-15-secession/</guid><description>15 Secession # The law of free association is a crucially important implication of the rights of private property (in physical material, and in our own bodies). For if we cannot freely associate with others on a mutually-voluntary basis, our property rights are to that extent abrogated.
The most serious denigration of property rights in persons and thus in free association is, of course, murder. No one favors such behavior (killing in self-defense is entirely another matter) so this is not at all controversial.</description></item><item><title>16 Legalize Drugs Now!</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-16-legalize-drugs-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-16-legalize-drugs-now/</guid><description>16 Legalize Drugs Now! An Analysis of the Benefits of Legalized Drugs # (with Meaghan Cussen)
Basic Constitutional Rights
Many argue that drug prohibition protects addicts from themselves by exerting parental control over their behavior. This government-enforced control, the anti-drug laws, strictly monitors addicts treatment of their own bodies. For example, the government decides that it wants to protect Fred Brown from destroying his body. The government, therefore, outlaws narcotics and, in effect, takes control of Fred’s body.</description></item><item><title>17 Libertarianism and Libertinism</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-17-libertarianism-and-libertinism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-2-human-rights/part-2-17-libertarianism-and-libertinism/</guid><description>17 Libertarianism and Libertinism # There is perhaps no greater confusion in all of political economy than that between libertarianism and libertinism. That they are commonly taken for one another is an understatement of the highest order. For several reasons, it is difficult to compare and contrast libertarianism and libertinism. First and most important, on some issues the two views do closely resemble one another, at least superficially. Second—perhaps purely by accident, perhaps due to etymological considerations—the two words not only sound alike, but are spelled almost identically.</description></item><item><title>18 Watch Your Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-18-watch-your-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-18-watch-your-language/</guid><description>18 Watch Your Language
Language is crucial to clear communication. It makes distinctions. We can hardly express ourselves without it. Our very thoughts can either be brought forth, or not, depending upon whether we have sufficient verbiage with which to attain this end. If the pen is mightier than the sword because it can determine the direction in which this weapon is aimed, then words are even mightier than the pen, for without the former the latter is useless.</description></item><item><title>19 Taking Back the Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-19-taking-back-the-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-19-taking-back-the-language/</guid><description>19 Taking Back the Language # In my last column,1 I claimed that language was important in the ideological battle for the free society. If we allow our “friends” on the statist left to seize the linguistic high ground, we make the battle more difficult for ourselves. We must use words which help us make the case for laissez faire capitalism, not those insisted upon by the other side. Let us now continue this process of “deconstructing” language to these ends with some more examples.</description></item><item><title>20 Word Watch</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-20-word-watch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-20-word-watch/</guid><description>20 Word Watch # Stakeholder
A new word has crept into our lexicon, courtesy of our friends on the left. It is “stakeholder” and it is the entering wedge of yet another attack on private property rights.
In the good old days, a firm had contractual obligations to its suppliers, to its employees, and to its customers. The only obligation it had to its neighbors was the one we all have to each other: to refrain from threatening or engaging in initiatory violence against them and their rightfully owned property.</description></item><item><title>21 Continuing to Watch Our Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-21-continuing-to-watch-our-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-21-continuing-to-watch-our-language/</guid><description>21 Continuing to Watch Our Language # In past columns on Watching Your Language,1 I made the point that it is important for us who espouse the freedom philosophy to be aware of the importance of language. If we get pushed into the linguistic corner our intellectual enemies have prepared for us, it is even more difficult to make the case in favor of laissez faire capitalism. In these previous attempts to wrestle with this challenge, I tried to set the record straight with regard to the following words and phrases: Ms.</description></item><item><title>22 Voluntary Taxes</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-22-voluntary-taxes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-22-voluntary-taxes/</guid><description>22 Voluntary Taxes: Abusive Language and Politicians # (with William Barnett)
In his March 20, 2002 letter to the Wall Street Journal “‘Tough-Guy’ Proposals for Indiana’s Budget,” that state’s Governor Frank O’Bannon calls “for increases in two minor, voluntary taxes—on cigarettes and riverboat admissions.”
“Voluntary taxation?” “Voluntary taxation” is an oxymoron if ever there was one; it is similar to “jumbo shrimp,” “an important trifle,” or “a square circle.” “Voluntary taxation” is a downright contradiction in terms, since if there is anything that taxation is not, it is voluntary.</description></item><item><title>23 Language, Once Again: Civil War, Inclusive Language, Economic Warfare, National Wealth</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-23-language-once-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-23-language-once-again/</guid><description>23 Language, Once Again: Civil War, Inclusive Language, Economic Warfare, National Wealth # Civil War
What took place in 1861 in the U.S. was not a “civil war.” There were not two contending armies, each one trying to rule the other. Rather, this was a war over secession.
For an example of a true civil war we might consider the Spanish Civil War of 1936. There, two groups fought each other, and each wished to rule over the entire country.</description></item><item><title>Bibliography</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/04-bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/04-bibliography/</guid><description>Bibliography # Abedian, I., and B. Standish. 1985. “Poor Whites and the Role of the State: The Evidence,” South Africa Journal of Economics 52, no. 2.
Abella, Irving, and Harold Troper. 1982. None is Too Many: Canada and the Jews of Europe, 1933–1948, Toronto: Lester and Orpen Dennys.
Adams, Charles. 2000. When in the Course of Human Events: Arguing the Case for Southern Secession, New York: Rowman &amp;amp; Littlefield.</description></item></channel></rss>