<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Part Three: Language on LW Studio</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/</link><description>Recent content in Part Three: Language on LW Studio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>CC-BY-4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>18 Watch Your Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-18-watch-your-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-18-watch-your-language/</guid><description>&lt;p>18 Watch Your Language&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Language is crucial to clear communication. It makes distinctions. We can hardly express ourselves without it. Our very thoughts can either be brought forth, or not, depending upon whether we have sufficient verbiage with which to attain this end. If the pen is mightier than the sword because it can determine the direction in which this weapon is aimed, then words are even mightier than the pen, for without the former the latter is useless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>19 Taking Back the Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-19-taking-back-the-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-19-taking-back-the-language/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="19-taking-back-the-language">
 19 Taking Back the Language
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#19-taking-back-the-language">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In my last column,1 I claimed that language was important in the ideological battle for the free society. If we allow our “friends” on the statist left to seize the linguistic high ground, we make the battle more difficult for ourselves. We must use words which help us make the case for laissez faire capitalism, not those insisted upon by the other side. Let us now continue this process of “deconstructing” language to these ends with some more examples.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 Word Watch</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-20-word-watch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-20-word-watch/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="20-word-watch">
 20 Word Watch
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#20-word-watch">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stakeholder&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A new word has crept into our lexicon, courtesy of our friends on the left. It is “stakeholder” and it is the entering wedge of yet another attack on private property rights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the good old days, a firm had contractual obligations to its suppliers, to its employees, and to its customers. The only obligation it had to its neighbors was the one we all have to each other: to refrain from threatening or engaging in initiatory violence against them and their rightfully owned property.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>21 Continuing to Watch Our Language</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-21-continuing-to-watch-our-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-21-continuing-to-watch-our-language/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="21-continuing-to-watch-our-language">
 21 Continuing to Watch Our Language
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#21-continuing-to-watch-our-language">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In past columns on Watching Your Language,1 I made the point that it is important for us who espouse the freedom philosophy to be aware of the importance of language. If we get pushed into the linguistic corner our intellectual enemies have prepared for us, it is even more difficult to make the case in favor of laissez faire capitalism. In these previous attempts to wrestle with this challenge, I tried to set the record straight with regard to the following words and phrases: Ms., developing countries, rent-seeking, social justice, tax subsidies, property rights, filthy rich, privileged, unearned income, freeman, ultra, profiteer, book burning, stakeholder, getting something for nothing, free rider, swamps and prejudice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>22 Voluntary Taxes</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-22-voluntary-taxes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-22-voluntary-taxes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="22-voluntary-taxes-abusive-language-and-politicians">
 22 Voluntary Taxes: Abusive Language and Politicians
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#22-voluntary-taxes-abusive-language-and-politicians">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>(with William Barnett)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In his March 20, 2002 letter to the Wall Street Journal “‘Tough-Guy’ Proposals for Indiana’s Budget,” that state’s Governor Frank O’Bannon calls “for increases in two minor, voluntary taxes—on cigarettes and riverboat admissions.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Voluntary taxation?” “Voluntary taxation” is an oxymoron if ever there was one; it is similar to “jumbo shrimp,” “an important trifle,” or “a square circle.” “Voluntary taxation” is a downright contradiction in terms, since if there is anything that taxation is not, it is voluntary. The proof is, if you do not pay, your property is forcibly confiscated and/or you go to jail. “Coercive taxation” is a redundancy, because once you comprehend the former word in this phrase, you know the meaning of the latter is a constituent part of that understanding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>23 Language, Once Again: Civil War, Inclusive Language, Economic Warfare, National Wealth</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-23-language-once-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/part-3-language/part-3-23-language-once-again/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="23-language-once-again-civil-war-inclusive-language-economic-warfare-national-wealth">
 23 Language, Once Again: Civil War, Inclusive Language, Economic Warfare, National Wealth
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#23-language-once-again-civil-war-inclusive-language-economic-warfare-national-wealth">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Civil War&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What took place in 1861 in the U.S. was not a “civil war.” There were not two contending armies, each one trying to rule the other. Rather, this was a war over secession.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For an example of a true civil war we might consider the Spanish Civil War of 1936. There, two groups fought each other, and each wished to rule over the entire country. On the one side were the fascists, under Franco; on the other side were the communists.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>