<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on LW Studio</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on LW Studio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-tw</language><copyright>CC-BY-4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Acknowledgements</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/01-acknowledgements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/01-acknowledgements/</guid><description>Acknowledgements # This book could not have been published without the advice and contribution of many libertarian colleagues and friends.
We are most grateful to Llewellyn H. Rockwell, Jr., President of the Ludwig von Mises Institute, for helping us pursue this project and writing a wonderful Foreword.
We should like to thank the editors of the International Journal of Value-Based Management, Ethics, Place and Environment, Journal of Business Ethics, Journal of Social, Political and Economic Studies, Managerial Finance, International Journal of Social Economics, Journal of Libertarian Studies, American Journal of Economics and Sociology for permission to reprint Professor Block’s articles previously published by these prestigious journals.</description></item><item><title>Foreword</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/02-foreword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/02-foreword/</guid><description>Foreword # Murray Rothbard, in his life, was known as Mr. Libertarian. We can make a solid case that the title now belongs to Walter Block, a student of Rothbard’s whose own vita is as thick as a phone book, as diverse as Wikipedia. Whether he is writing on economic theory, ethics, political secession, drugs, roads, education, monetary policy, social theory, unions, political language, or anything else, his prose burns with a passion for this single idea: if human problems are to be solved, the solution is to be found by permitting greater liberty.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/03-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/03-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction # This book Building Blocks for Liberty: Critical Essays by Walter Block is dedicated to the notion that libertarianism is not only a political economic philosophy that is powerful and insightful, but it is also unique; it is neither of the right nor of the left (Walter Block, “Libertarianism is Unique; It Belongs Neither to the Right Nor the Left; A Critique of the Views of Long, Holcombe, and Baden on the left, Hoppe, Feser and Paul on the right,” Journal of Libertarian Studies, 2010).</description></item><item><title>Bibliography</title><link>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/04-bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raviwu.github.io/books-building-blocks-liberty/en/docs/04-bibliography/</guid><description>Bibliography # Abedian, I., and B. Standish. 1985. “Poor Whites and the Role of the State: The Evidence,” South Africa Journal of Economics 52, no. 2.
Abella, Irving, and Harold Troper. 1982. None is Too Many: Canada and the Jews of Europe, 1933–1948, Toronto: Lester and Orpen Dennys.
Adams, Charles. 2000. When in the Course of Human Events: Arguing the Case for Southern Secession, New York: Rowman &amp;amp; Littlefield.</description></item></channel></rss>